{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Ramadan is the ninth month of the Islamic calendar. A foundational pillar of practicing Islam is fasting during the month of Ramadan. This devotional act is observed by over a billion Muslims worldwide today. Fasting is a major act of worship, and it is a powerful means of cultivating God-consciousness in the heart and mind. Fasting has both physical and spiritual benefits, including purifying the soul, inspiring self-reflection, and increasing empathy and good works."
        },
        {
            "question": "When is Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Ramadan is the ninth month of the Islamic calendar, which follows the lunar system. As a natural phenomenon, lunar months vary in length, containing either 29 or 30 days. This means that the lunar year is 10 or 11 days shorter than the solar year, since months in the solar year often have 31 days. Ultimately, this means that those measuring against the solar calendar will perceive Ramadan as \u201cshifting\u201d a few days earlier each Gregorian year. In 2024, Ramadan will begin around March 11th and end around April 9th. The exact days are confirmed by the sighting of the new moon at the start of the month."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is Ramadan celebrated ?",
            "answer": "God says in the Qur\u2019an, \u201cRamadan is the month in which the Qur\u2019an was revealed, as guidance for humanity\u2026so whoever of you witnesses the month should fast it.\u201d  [2:185] Muslims therefore celebrate Ramadan by ritually fasting for the entire month in gratitude to God for His final revelation. By restricting the body\u2019s appetites during daylight hours, believers rejuvenate their spirituality, repair their religious conscience, and cultivate their devotion to God. This is the most significant objective of the fast: restoring the centrality of God in our lives."
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you observe Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Muslims observe Ramadan by abstaining from food, drink, smoking, and sexual intimacy\u2014all out of devotion to their Creator. They are also called to practice self-restraint and respond to every situation with patience and kindness. The Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa informed us, \u201cWhoever does not give up lying and acting dishonestly, then [know that] God has no need for this person to give up food and drink (i.e., fasting).\u201d [Sahih al-Bukhari #1903] In addition to fasting, Muslims also celebrate Ramadan by reciting and studying the Qur\u2019an, performing acts of service, and giving to charity. Many people read the Qur\u2019an cover to cover multiple times over the course of the month. Believers complete their readings individually and in nightly congregations that take place in virtually every mosque on the planet. This is all in emulation of the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa, who would annually rehearse with the archangel Gabriel all that had been revealed to him of the Qur\u2019an."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the purpose of fasting in Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Muslims fast for the entire month in gratitude to God for His final revelation. By restricting the body\u2019s appetites during daylight hours, believers rejuvenate their spirituality, repair their religious conscience, and cultivate their devotion to God. This is the most significant objective of the fast: restoring the centrality of God in our lives. Ramadan is a period of practicing extra awareness about all the things that could soil our spirituality and fuel the ego that feeds off our catering to its appetites throughout the year. Vices are always forbidden, but we work with even greater dedication to avoid them and excel in devotion, kindness, patience, and forgiveness in Ramadan. Such inner purity is the intended result of fasting."
        },
        {
            "question": "How long do you fast in Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Healthy adult Muslims fast from before sunrise to sunset. During this time, Muslims cannot drink (even water), eat, smoke, or be sexually intimate, out of devotion to God."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is required to fast during Ramadan?",
            "answer": "All healthy, able-bodied, and of-age Muslims must observe and fast the month of Ramadan. However there are exception such as children who have not reached puberty. In addition travelers, pregnant or nursing women, or those who are sick and are unable to are not required to fast but must make up the fast later on."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are there any exceptions or exemptions from fasting?",
            "answer": "Yes. Islam has a merciful and pragmatic legal framework that allows many exceptions to the rules. The categories of people exempted from fasting are an excellent example of that. Children who haven\u2019t reached the age of puberty are not required to fast, although some like to practice and participate in Ramadan activities. Pregnant women and nursing mothers who struggle to fast, as well as those who are traveling, are allowed to break their fast and make up for the days they missed in Ramadan later on in the year. In addition, women experiencing menses are allowed to rest from the five daily prayers and from fasting."
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times do Muslims pray during Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Muslims maintain the standard five daily prayers, but strive to increase the amount of worship they perform during Ramadan. In addition to the five daily prayers, many Muslims perform extra nightly prayers called Taraweeh and additional forms of worship such as tahajjud, itikaf, and an increase in reading the Qur\u2019an."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the Taraweeh prayers?",
            "answer": "Taraweeh are additional prayers performed nightly during Ramadan. They are optional prayers. Taraweeh is prayed in sets of two rakats each, in the same way Muslims pray the standard salah (prayers). Most mosques around the world hold Taraweeh prayers, providing each community with a chance to listen and reflect on the recitation of the Qur\u2019an behind an expert reciter throughout the blessed month."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Laylatul Qadr?",
            "answer": "Laylatul Qadr can be translated as The Night of Decree or The Night of Power. In the context of this holy night, some scholars define \u201cqadr\u201d as \u201cdecree\u201d (qadar). In other words, it is the night in which the destiny of each person--their sustenance, lifespan, and other critical matters--is decided and sealed for the coming year. Other scholars define \u201cqadr\u201d as \u201cpower,\u201d indicating the greatness of the night. Similarly, some who interpret \u201cqadr\u201d as \u201cpower\u201d do so to bring attention to the fact that righteous deeds performed during this night are far more powerful than they would be on any other night."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is Laylatul Qadr important?",
            "answer": "Laylatul Qadr, often translated as \u201cThe Night of Power,\u201d has a number of significant attributes. Most importantly, the Qur\u2019an was revealed in its entirety on this night. Laylatul Qadr has also been described as a gift for the Prophet Muhammad\u2019s community. There is a hadith that states: \u201cThe Messenger of Allah\u2026was shown the lifespans of the people (who had gone) before him, or what Allah willed of that, and it was as if the lives of the people of his community had become too short for them to be able to do as many good actions as others before them had been able to do with their long lives, so Allah gave him Laylat al-Qadr, which is better than a thousand months.\u201d"
        },
        {
            "question": "When is Laylatul Qadr?",
            "answer": "The precise night on which Laylatul Qadr occurs has not been mentioned. The Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa said, \u201cSearch for Laylatul Qadr in the odd nights of the last 10 nights of Ramadan.\u201d There is tremendous wisdom in not knowing exactly when it occurs. As Ibn Qudamah al-Maqdisi (d. 620 AH/1223 CE) writes, \u201cGod has concealed this night from the Muslim community (ummah) so that they may strive in seeking it and performing worship throughout the month in the hopes of catching it."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is charity important during Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Muslims focus on increasing all of their good actions during the holy month, but particularly increase their generosity through making donations, helping the needy, serving the hungry, and paying a mandatory charity (Zakat al-Fitr) to the poor before the end of Ramadan. This spirit of giving comes from the sympathy we feel for those who have less when we experience hunger and deprivation ourselves, and also from deepening our relationship with God\u2019s word, and understanding the vast mercy and generosity inherent in the nature of God. It is authentically reported that, \u201cThe Prophet \ufdfa was the most generous of all the people, and he used to become even more generous in Ramadan.\u201d [Sahih al-Bukhari #3554]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Zakat al-Fitr?",
            "answer": "Zakat al-Fitr is a donation made before Eid al-Fitr. It ensures that even those who don\u2019t have much are able to eat and celebrate during the holiday."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Eid al-Fitr?",
            "answer": "Eid al-Fitr occurs at the end of Ramadan. After an entire month of fasting and extra prayer, Muslims are sad to bid Ramadan and its spiritual atmosphere good-bye, but also excited to celebrate their efforts with a holiday. The festivities begin early on Eid day with the traditional takbeerat and communal prayers. Celebrants show up in their loveliest clothing to pray together, embrace all of their friends, and wish each other \u201cEid Mubarak\u201d (Blessed Eid). After the Eid prayer, specific ways of celebrating vary across a plethora of Muslim cultures, but whether it\u2019s knafeh or donuts, you can be sure that there will be lots of feasting on delicious foods, exchanging gifts, and quality time spent together with family and community. In 2024, Eid al-Fitr will take place on April 10th. This date is tentative until the sighting of the new moon at the start of the month."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Islam?",
            "answer": "Islam is a faith of pure monotheism that builds on the messages of previous prophets sent to humankind throughout history. It is a continuation of the same message preached by all of God\u2019s prophets \u2014 ending with the final prophet, Muhammad \ufdfa \u2014 calling people to believe and worship in the one, true God alone. It is the original religion of Adam, Abraham, Moses, and Jesus that clarifies the purpose of creation and guides us on how to live a Godly, righteous life. As the final message from God to humanity, Islam is a manifestation of the Divine covenant made before the creation of the world where every soul gathered to recognize God as their Lord. In the Islamic worldview, this knowledge is coded into our subconscious makeup. Through testifying one\u2019s faith, we reaffirm our witness of God\u2019s Lordship and commit to living out a life according to and in line with His will. The Qur\u2019an, God\u2019s final words revealed to Prophet Muhammad, and prophetic teachings (Sunnah) offer guidance on how to adhere to the message."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does Islam mean?",
            "answer": "The word \u2018Islam\u2019 is an Arabic term encompassing the meanings of submission, surrender, and peace."
        },
        {
            "question": "What do Muslims believe?",
            "answer": "In Islam, faith is composed of six core articles of faith, commonly referred to as the pillars of faith. They are: Belief in God, Belief in angels, Belief in Divinely revealed books, Belief in the Messengers of God, Belief in the Day of Judgement, Belief in Divine Decree."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Allah?",
            "answer": "Allah is simply the Arabic word for God. The word \u2018Allah\u2019 does not have a gender or a plural form, indicating God\u2019s uniqueness from all creation and His absolute oneness. Allah is also the term for \u2018God\u2019 used by non-Muslim Arabic speakers such as Arab Christians. Muslims believe God is exalted above everything else in the universe, unrestricted by time and space, and distinct in His attributes. He is All-Powerful and All-Wise, with full control over the universe, as it was created by His will. As taught in the Qur\u2019an, Allah is the Lord of all the Worlds; humanity\u2019s Creator, Nourisher, and Sustainer, whom all should worship and love. The 99 Beautiful Names of God encapsulate the various divine attributes through which God has described Himself. Allah is not restricted to these names alone; rather, they are a means by which someone can begin to know Him. God, above all else in the Islamic worldview, is the Most Merciful and the Most Kind (these are the names most often repeated in the Qur\u2019an and in daily prayers), the Most Loving, and the Source of all peace, reliance, and refuge. The gift of worship is from His bounty to keep mankind forever connected to Him. \u201cHe is God: there is no god other than Him. It is He who knows what is hidden as well as what is in the open, He is the Lord of Mercy, the Giver of Mercy. He is God: there is no god other than Him, the Controller, the Holy One, Source of Peace, Granter of Security, Guardian over all, the Almighty, the Compeller, the Truly Great; God is far above anything they consider to be His partner. He is God: the Creator, the Originator, the Shaper. The best names belong to Him. Everything in the heavens and earth glorifies Him: He is the Almighty, the Wise.\u201d [Quran, 59:22-24]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Qur\u2019an?",
            "answer": "The Qur\u2019an is the speech of God revealed to Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa through the Angel Gabriel (Jibril) over a period of 23 years. The Qur\u2019an constitutes the final revealed message from God through the last prophet and messenger sent to the world. The Qur\u2019an is both miraculously preserved and inimitable. In other words, what we know as the Qur\u2019an today is the exact same text that was revealed to Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa. The Qur\u2019an is also miraculous in that it is impossible for human beings to imitate, contains no errors or contradictions, accurately foretells future events, describes matters of the natural world unknown to human beings at the time of revelation, and contains benefit for all human beings."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Prophet Muhammad?",
            "answer": "Muhammad \ufdfa, the son of Abdullah, was the final prophet and messenger of God. He was born in 570 CE in Mecca, where he eventually received the final revealed book sent to humanity, the Qur\u2019an, and began calling people to the religion of Islam. Despite facing many challenges and being met with rejection and persecution during his life and prophetic mission, he unfailingly exhibited beautiful character, rose above enmity and insult, and accomplished a stunning array of achievements. He is the most beloved of all creation to God, and is the greatest of not only all of God\u2019s prophets and messengers, but the entirety of creation. Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa is often described as the \u201cfounder of Islam,\u201d but this is not exactly accurate. Islam did not begin with his prophetic mission. Instead, it is more accurate to say he was sent to confirm and restore the messages of previous prophets and scriptures in their original, uncorrupted forms. All of the messengers of God, from Adam to Jesus to Muhammad, conveyed the same fundamental message of monotheism and good works and are brothers in prophethood."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the five pillars of Islam?",
            "answer": "The five pillars of Islam are: the testimony of faith, prayer, zakat, fasting of Ramadan, and performing hajj. Islam can be imagined as a building supported by five pillars. Each of these pillars are necessary for the building of Islam to stand. Without them, the structure collapses. These pillars are: Shahada: Testifying that there is no god but Allah (God), and that Muhammad \ufdfa is the final Messenger of God, Salat: Praying five daily prayers, Zakat: Donating an obligatory amount of charity, Sawm: Fasting in Ramadan, Hajj: Making the pilgrimage to the Ka\u2019aba. Everything else in Islam is built upon these five foundational pillars."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Islamic testimony of faith (shahada)?",
            "answer": "The shahada is to believe in the message of Islam and declare that: There is no god but Allah (God), and Muhammad \ufdfa is the Messenger of God. This testimony of faith, known in Arabic as the shahada, encapsulates the religion of Islam. It must be affirmed in the heart and uttered by the tongue. The shahada is a declaration of monotheism (tawhid) stating that there is absolutely no deity except for the one, true, creator: God. He has no partners in divinity, no children, and none are worthy of worship except Him. It is also a statement of acceptance that Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa is God\u2019s final prophet and messenger."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why do Muslims pray daily?",
            "answer": "Prayer (salah) forges and sustains an essential connection between a person and their Creator. Muslims have been instructed by God to pray five times daily within prescribed times. The Qur\u2019an informs us that the primary reason for our creation and existence is to worship God, and these required five daily prayers are, in essence, a foundational fulfillment of this existential purpose."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is zakat?",
            "answer": "Zakat refers to an obligatory portion of wealth a Muslim must give annually to the Islamic law details the various types of wealth that are zakat-eligible, how it is calculated, and the specific categories of people eligible to receive it. Zakat is frequently mentioned alongside prayer (salat) throughout the Qur\u2019an and was a ubiquitous feature of all prophetic calls. Among the five pillars of Islam, zakat is unique in that, in addition to being an act of devotion to God, it plays an important social function. While things like prayer and fasting are, on their face, individual acts of ritual devotion, zakat directly benefits one\u2019s community and, as an institution, wields immense economically and socially transformative power."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is sadaqa?",
            "answer": "Sadaqa refers to any act of charity or giving. Charity is one of the most highly emphasized acts and virtues in Islam and bears a great deal of spiritual and societal benefit. The widespread practice of Muslims establishing charitable endowments across Muslim societies is just one example of how this emphasis upon charitable giving manifests. While the default conception of sadaqa is often monetary in nature, Islam outlines an expansive understanding of charity that extends to many non-monetary acts of giving such as spreading joy, meeting people with a smile, or merely speaking a kind word. In fact, Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa said that, \u201cEvery good deed is charity. Verily, it is a good deed to meet your brother with a cheerful face, and to pour what is left from your bucket into the vessel of your brother.\u201d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What holidays do Muslims celebrate?",
            "answer": "Muslims celebrate two major holidays: Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha. Muslim days of celebration occur at the conclusion of seasons of worship. The day of Eid al-Fitr is celebrated at the end of Ramadan, while Eid al-Adha is celebrated at the conclusion of Hajj. These days are intended to be days of festivity and joy for Muslims, and are distinguished from other days since one is not allowed to fast on them. Fridays are also weekly holy days for Muslims, as Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa said, \u201cAllah has made this day of Friday a celebration for the Muslims.\u201d"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Ramadan is the 9th month of the Hijri, or Islamic lunar calendar, during which Muslims are obligated to fast each day of the entire month. Fasting entails abstaining from food, drink, and intimacy from dawn to sunset. All sane, mature Muslims are obligated to fast unless they have a legitimate excuse (due to travel, illness, etc.), in which case Islamic law details if and how they are to make up for missed Ramadan fasts. The month of Ramadan is also the month in which the revelation of God\u2019s final message to humanity, the Qur\u2019an, began. The Qur\u2019an was first revealed on the Night of Decree (laylat al-qadr), which is described as the greatest night of the entire year."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why do Muslims have to fast for a full month?",
            "answer": "Muslims fast for the entire month because God prescribed this to be the length of the fasting period. During prayer five times a day, Muslims face the Ka\u2019aba in Mecca. Rituals like this were prescribed by God and, thus, we follow them. Likewise, Muslims fast for the entire month because God prescribed that this be the length of the fast: Ramadan is the month in which the Quran was revealed as a guide for humanity, with clear proofs of guidance and the standard \u02f9to distinguish between right and wrong\u02fa. So whoever is present this month, let them fast\u2026 [Qur\u2019an, 2:185] The aim and purpose of fasting is to develop a greater sense of consciousness of God. Fasting also teaches Muslims self-restraint, and enables people to experience hunger and, hopefully, a greater sense of empathy for those who are less fortunate."
        },
        {
            "question": "Do Muslims fast outside of Ramadan?",
            "answer": "Muslims can voluntarily fast outside of the month of Ramadan, but are not required to do so. Fasting outside of Ramadan is an extremely virtuous and highly rewarded practice that Muslims are encouraged to do if they can. In fact, it was Prophet Muhammad\u2019s \ufdfa regular practice to fast on Mondays and Thursdays, three days at the middle of each lunar month, and a number of other days throughout the year."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the significance of the Hajj pilgrimage?",
            "answer": "Hajj is one of the five pillars of Islam. All Muslims must perform the Hajj once in a lifetime, if they are physically and financially able to do so. Among other things, the pilgrimage is a commemoration of the legacy and sacrifices of Prophet Abraham (Ibrahim), peace be upon him, and his family. The rituals of Hajj are full of powerful symbolism and lessons, and experiencing them can bring about profound spiritual change."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Jesus in Islam?",
            "answer": "Jesus, the son of Mary, is considered a prophet and a messenger of God in Islam. Muslims believe that Jesus (peace be upon him) was not only one of God\u2019s prophets and messengers, but that he was among an elite category among them, distinguished for their extraordinary resolve and determination. This category includes Noah, Abraham, Moses, and Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa. Islam teaches that Jesus was born of a miraculous birth to the Virgin Mary (who is herself highly revered in Islam). He is the Messiah (al-Masih) and the Word and Spirit of God, who performed numerous miracles including healing the blind and lepers, feeding multitudes, and resurrecting the dead. Muslims also believe in the Second Coming, and hold that Jesus will return to Earth shortly before the Day of Judgment to kill the False Messiah (al-Masih al-Dajjal, the Antichrist). He will rule the world justly, and usher in an era of unprecedented peace and prosperity. Muslims further believe that Jesus enjoys a special connection and proximity to Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa and his nation (i.e. Muslims): He will return to lead and pass away among Prophet Muhammad\u2019s followers. Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa also declared that he is \u201cthe nearest of people to Jesus,\u201d that they both came with the same religion, and that, \u201cthere was no prophet [sent] between us.\u201d Muslims reject, however, that Jesus was crucified, that he is the son of God, and that he is a god himself."
        },
        {
            "question": "Do Muslims believe in the crucifixion of Jesus?",
            "answer": "No, Muslims do not believe that Jesus was crucified or killed. While Muslims do believe that Jesus and his followers were persecuted by authorities in his time, and that Jesus suffered betrayal at the hands of some of his own people, Islam teaches that Jesus was miraculously saved from crucifixion and ascended to the heavens where he remains alive."
        },
        {
            "question": "Do Muslims believe in the Holy Spirit?",
            "answer": "Muslims believe in the Holy Spirit (al-Ruh al-Qudus) with reference to the Angel Gabriel (Jibril) and not as a part of a trinitarian godhead. It was through the Holy Spirit that Jesus was able to perform numerous miracles. However, Muslims do not believe that the Holy Spirit is a part of a trinitarian godhead, nor a separate god to be worshiped or prayed to. Rather, the Holy Spirit, Gabriel, is a creation of God and under His complete control."
        },
        {
            "question": "Do Muslims believe in Heaven and Hell?",
            "answer": "Yes. Belief in Heaven and Hell are essential aspects of Islamic belief. Islam teaches that, after death, all of humanity will eventually be resurrected on the Day of Judgement, judged according to their individual actions, and sent to Paradise or the Hellfire. Paradise is a place of eternal bliss, beauty, pleasure, and happiness, filled with delights that \u201cno eye has ever seen, no ear has ever heard, and what no human mind has ever imagined.\u201d It is a place free of any pain, suffering, sadness, or death. Hell is a terrifying place filled with pain, suffering, and misery. Some who enter it will eventually be taken out and placed in Heaven, while others will remain eternally."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are there dietary restrictions in Islam?",
            "answer": "Yes. Muslims are prohibited from consuming pork, alcohol, and substances that impair the mind, as well as those that do not meet proper standards (detailed below). While an exhaustive treatment of Islamic dietary rules is beyond our scope here, it suffices to say that Islam\u2019s prohibition regarding food, drink, and substances extend beyond merely pork and alcohol. For instance, Muslims are not permitted to use or ingest any type of intoxicating substance for merely recreational purposes. Additionally, certain types of animals (such as animals of prey) are not permitted for consumption. Even animals whose meat is permissible, if not slaughtered properly, becomes impermissible to consume."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does halal mean?",
            "answer": "Halal refers to that which is permissible to Muslims. Halal means what is allowed, in contrast to what is referred to as haram, not allowed for Muslims. However, it is commonly used to refer to foods (especially meat) that Muslims are permitted to consume."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are kosher and halal the same?",
            "answer": "There are many similarities between what is kosher (permissible for Jews to consume) and what is halal (permissible for Muslims to consume), but there are also significant differences. The two dietary codes diverge on issues such as alcohol and food pairings. Kosher laws generally do not prohibit alcohol, whereas Islamic law strictly prohibits its consumption, even when used for cooking. Unlike Jews, Muslims do not require the separation of dairy and meat products. However, both Islamic and Jewish dietary rules prohibit consuming pork and pork-derived products. They require similar ritual slaughtering procedures as well as the draining of the slaughtered animal\u2019s blood, and both prohibit carrion (an animal found dead before slaughter). Many of the animals Muslims are allowed to slaughter are also permitted for Jews."
        },
        {
            "question": "Is divorce allowed in Islam?",
            "answer": "Divorce is allowed in Islam. While reconciliation between spouses is highly encouraged, and divorce has been described by the Prophet \ufdfa as being, \u201cThe most detestable of permissible things to God,\u201d it is nonetheless allowed according to Islamic law. A husband may unilaterally terminate a marriage through the process of talaq (legal divorce). In the case of talaq, women are entitled to financial support through the end of their waiting period as well as their stipulated deferred dower and a suitable gift (mut\u2019ah). Should the couple have children, the man must also cover expenses of his children regardless of custody."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam promote violence?",
            "answer": "No, Islam does not promote unprovoked violence. Islam governs by a primary set of principles known as maqasid ash-shariah: the preservation of religion, life, intellect, progeny, and property. The value of human life is emphasized in Islam\u2019s sacred texts, the Qur\u2019an and Sunnah. The Qur\u2019an equates a single murder with the killing of humankind at large, and equates saving a single life with rescuing all of humanity. The Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa defined the faithful as \u201cthose most restrained from violence\u201d. Islam even forbids sports that use animals as targets, or involve striking the face of a fellow human being. However, tyranny and crimes against humanity are an unfortunate fact of the human condition, so Islam engages this reality by sometimes allowing physical force as a deterrent, and regulating it with ethical parameters, to ensure the best possible outcome for society and the world."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam permit the killing of civilians?",
            "answer": "Islam does not permit the killing of civilians. No classical Muslim scholar has ever condoned the killing of civilians, even in the midst of a justified war. Indiscriminate acts of violence against civilians, which are often attributed to Islam, have zero precedent in Islamic teachings. It is for this reason that car bombings, suicide bombings, mass shootings, and other crimes committed by self-identified Muslims are so strongly condemned by Muslim leaders and communities around the world. In Islam, the deliberate targeting of civilians in war is categorically unjustified, going against both the higher aims of Islamic law to protect all life, as well as the universal Islamic maxim which criminalizes any and all avoidable harm."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does jihad mean?",
            "answer": "Jihad is a broad Arabic term that, at its core, means to expend one\u2019s efforts in a good cause despite the adversity involved. Islam\u2019s scriptures use the term jihad in a variety of contexts. The Qur\u2019an refers to the jihad of preaching an unpopular truth (25:52), the jihad of pursuing guidance despite obstacles (29:69), and the jihad of resisting the persecution of oneself (2:190) and others (4:75). The Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa also used the term jihad in the context of speaking truth to power, seeking knowledge, selflessly serving one\u2019s parents, and battling the evil within one\u2019s soul."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is jihad misinterpreted as terrorism?",
            "answer": "Armed jihad is a last resort governed by strict rules. The groups we see today claiming to be performing jihad violate those rules. Armed conflict could fall under \u201cjihad\u201d when certain conditions deem it necessary, such as the faith or safety of Muslims being physically threatened, human rights being overrun, or when people\u2019s freedom to practice, preach, and embrace Islam is suppressed. Islam has strict legal conditions for the use of force as a last resort, which includes the safety of civilians and non-military property, and the forbidding of treachery, mutilation, and plunder. These rules of military jihad, in many ways, preceded what would later become the modern just-war theory."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does the Qur\u2019an say to kill the non-believers?",
            "answer": "This verse is frequently quoted out of context and with a lack of understanding. One of the most misquoted sentences in the Qur\u2019an is: \u201cKill them wherever you find them\u201d (2:191). Reading this passage in its full context, and knowing how extensively peace, justice, and compassion permeate the Qur\u2019anic message, is sufficient to neutralize the misuse of this verse above. This verse is speaking about active combatants (2:190), and specifically attackers whom the believers feared they would be forced to confront in a place which the Qur\u2019an deemed a sacred precinct; a place so sacred that even cutting a tree or frightening a bird was prohibited therein. Therefore, this verse simply establishes a concession to fend off assailants, regardless of where they may be encountered."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam allow preemptive war?",
            "answer": "Islam allows preemptive war only after a fair declaration of war, where a credible threat exists, never in violation of a peace treaty or truce, and never with those inclined to peace. The Western concept of preemptive war, or a war launched to neutralize an actual threat or impending attack, is similar to the concept of \u201coffensive jihad\u201d (jihad al-talab) in Islam. Offensive jihad is when a Muslim country\u2019s army engages another military force beyond its borders. This must occur after a fair declaration of war (i.e., where a credible threat is made), never in violation of a peace treaty or truce, and never with those inclined to peace."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are there specific codes of war in Islam?",
            "answer": "Yes, Islam has many regulations to minimize the destruction of any war. The loss of life is minimized by strict rules against targeting civilians and noncombatants. The loss of property is minimized by rules against pillaging lands and cutting down trees. Also, prisoners of war must be treated humanely, and believers are encouraged to release them unconditionally, or for a reasonable ransom, or by providing them realistic ways to free themselves through fair labor. The ultimate and overarching goal of Islamic law is to minimize harm and maximize benefit for society as a whole. At times, this may require taking up arms to secure peace. In those cases, sacred laws restrain Muslim armies from taking advantage of an enemy and hold them to the most morally upright codes of conduct in war. The Qur\u2019an also states that wars should be ended as quickly as possible: \u201cAnd if they incline to peace, then incline to it [also] and rely upon Allah. Indeed, it is He who is the Hearing, the Knowing.\u201d (8:61)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Did Islam spread through violence and forced conversions?",
            "answer": "The spread of Islam occurred through religious propagation, trade, intermarriage, migration, the universality of Islam, and its emphasis on justice and unity. Historians have widely discredited the narrative that Islam is widespread in the world today because of forced conversions. While exceptional cases of forced conversions did exist, these were clear violations of Islamic guidelines and never the norm. Forced conversions are clearly forbidden in Islam. God says in the Qur\u2019an, \u201cThere is no compulsion in religion,\u201d (2:256). Forcing someone to practice Islam defeats the purpose of the religion\u2014for individuals to build a sincere and genuine relationship with their Creator."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Islam treat religious minorities?",
            "answer": "Religious tolerance was historically a hallmark of Muslim societies. Religious minorities were known in Islamic history as dhimmis, or the \u201cprotected class\u201d, which reflected the fact that under Islamic law, they enjoyed the dhimmah (protection) of God, in which they could live in security and practice their religion without harassment. The presence of other religious communities within Muslim majority countries today is perhaps one of the clearest proofs against the claim that Islam requires non-Muslims to convert or face the sword. Many non-Muslim minorities had thriving communities within the capitals of major cities under Islamic control for centuries (there were Christian quarters in Damascus, Jerusalem, and Coptic Cairo, for example) where they operated under their own religious court systems."
        },
        {
            "question": "Is blasphemy punishable by death?",
            "answer": "The Qur\u2019an tells Muslims who encounter blasphemy or offenses to God and His religion to simply turn away until the conversation changes (6:68, 4:140). When the pagans of Quraysh would call the Prophet \u2018mudhammam\u2019 (the disgraced) instead of his name Muhammad (the oft-praised), he would gracefully say to his followers, \u201cAren\u2019t you amazed that God has even averted the insults of the Quraysh? They revile a man named Mudhammam, while I am Muhammad!\u201d (Sahih Bukhari). Historically, an attack on the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa meant a rebellion against the constitution of the Muslim state. While Muslim scholars had different opinions about the penalty for insulting the Prophet \ufdfa, major early scholars such as Abu Hanifah and al-Bukhari believed there should be no punishment at all, because a non-Muslim\u2019s disbelief in Islam is already assumed. Scholars note that those executed in the Prophet\u2019s \ufdfa lifetime were warmongers and menaces to society, not simply insulters or peaceful opponents. Also, legal punishments in Islam are only enforceable by a governing authority, and so the duty of the average Muslim is to adopt the Prophet\u2019s gentle character, clarify misinformation about him, and advocate for a harmonious society that rejects the desecration of any religious symbols or personalities."
        },
        {
            "question": "Is apostasy punishable by death in Islam?",
            "answer": "Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa did not punish a single apostate in his entire life solely for leaving the faith. Following this precedent, many contemporary Muslim jurists choose not to punish apostates for leaving Islam. Punishing apostasy has roots in Judaism, Christianity, and Islam. It may be difficult to grasp why this was ever considered necessary, due to how little religion affects wider society in our secular age. In pre-modern times, religious identity played a major role in defining individuals and nations. As a result, leaving one\u2019s faith would be seen as a rebellion against public order and a subversion of the common good. For example, European Christians who embraced Islam were often referred to as \u201cRenegades\u201d and would risk their lives to remain in Europe, as a religious conversion was widely seen as treason and a declaration of hostility. In the past, Muslim jurists have held that clear apostasy was a capital crime for which a person may be killed. This does not mean that mobs of Muslims carried out executions, or that officials hunted down apostates inquisition-style. This could only be acted on by the government, and they were only to act on public claims of apostasy, and confirmed offenders were urged to recant as a way to completely avoid any consequences. Many contemporary Muslim jurists choose not to punish apostates for leaving Islam, in accordance with international agreements on religious freedoms, as well as the precedent set by Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa, who did not punish a single apostate in his entire life solely for leaving the faith."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam Allow Honor Killings?",
            "answer": "Islamic law has a zero tolerance policy on honor killings, drawing on clear rulings set by the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa. According to Islamic law, any husband who kills his wife or illicit partner has committed murder, even if he was indirectly involved in her death. Islam is not the culprit, but part of the solution, for honor crimes. Islam effectively reforms the cultural and legal systems that perpetuate honor killings, or fail at combating them, through its serious warnings against violating the safety of innocent people in general, and condemning the abuse of women in particular. Violence against women is a universal problem that extends far beyond a specific religion or region. To depict it as inherent to Muslim societies as a result of Islamic teachings is not only dishonest, but works to downplay the true extent of this global problem. Such narratives only get in the way of efforts to protect the safety and dignity of all women, and disparage the Islamic teachings that have lessened the prevalence of those who prey on women in this tragic way."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Sharia?",
            "answer": "Sharia is the set of Islamic laws that encompass both the religious and secular practices of Muslims. It is often redundantly referred to as 'Sharia law.' Sharia encompasses the legal dimensions of Muslim life and is akin to halakhah (Jewish law). The term 'Sharia' carries the meaning of being 'the Way' or 'the path' towards water. Sharia covers two broad domains: The rights of God, and the rights of man. It informs and regulates most aspects of Muslim life, from how one prays and washes, to how one governs and does business."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the history of Sharia?",
            "answer": "Sharia (Islamic law) developed after the passing of the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa as scholars relied on Islamic sources and legal reasoning to derive rulings and guidance in the face of Muslim questions around law, ethics, and ritual. During the lifetime of the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa, disputes and questions on everything from creed to law to social and political affairs could be settled in his presence. With his passing, however, Muslims faced the challenge of navigating questions, problems, and disputes without his guidance. This dilemma led to the development of what is known as the Sharia\u2013a guide that informs us of how to live our lives in accordance with God\u2019s wishes but in the absence of prophecy."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where does Sharia come from?",
            "answer": "Sharia (Islamic law and legal rulings) are based on the sacred texts of the Qur\u2019an and Sunnah, as well as external scholarly sources. External sources include, but are not limited to, scholarly consensus (ijm\u0101\u02bf) and analogical reasoning (qiy\u0101s). This is the basis on which Islamic law is constructed. The terms Sharia and Islamic law are often used interchangeably, and refer to the many legal, moral, and ritualistic rulings found in or derived from the Qur\u2019an and Sunnah. The process and jurisprudential activity of deriving and interpreting rulings is known as fiqh. The Sharia is not, however, merely a body of static, fixed law codes lifted directly from the Quran and Sunnah."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is fiqh?",
            "answer": "Fiqh is the process of deriving and interpreting Islamic law (Sharia). Linguistically, the Arabic word 'fiqh' bears the meaning of 'deep understanding or comprehension.' In the technical sense, fiqh refers to the process of deriving and interpreting Islamic law, as well as the body of rulings that emerge from this process. It is through fiqh that we come to know the Sharia and how to apply it in our lives. Fiqh is used to clarify the details of what God wants of Muslims and how to live in conformity with His will."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Sharia relate to rituals of worship?",
            "answer": "The Sharia, as it is interpreted through fiqh, lays out how a Muslim must worship God. As worshippers, Muslims must pray, fast in Ramadan, distribute zakat (obligatory charity), and perform the pilgrimage to Mecca. The Sharia lays out these obligations and guides Muslims on how to properly carry them out. It clarifies questions concerning ritual, such as how to pray if one is injured, or in what situations one is exempt from fasting. Manuals of Islamic law and curricula of Muslim scholarship typically cover matters pertaining to ritual first, before delving into matters of society."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Sharia relate to society?",
            "answer": "The Sharia provides timeless guidance and instruction concerning every aspect of life. From marriage and divorce, to dietary guidelines and dress, to crime and punishment, to business and commercial transactions and inheritance, the Sharia provides ethical guidance and legal instruction concerning every conceivable facet of Muslim life."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a fatwa?",
            "answer": "A fatwa is a specific legal opinion or ruling issued by a qualified Muslim scholar based on interpreting the Sharia. A fatwa (pl. fatawa) is usually issued in response to a specific question or circumstance. For example, if one is unsure about whether a certain type of drink is permissible, they can ask a Muslim scholar, who will examine the matter and provide a ruling on the drink\u2019s permissibility or impermissibility. The scholar\u2019s response would be called a fatwa."
        },
        {
            "question": "Is the Sharia uniform and unchanging?",
            "answer": "Some aspects of the Sharia are universal and timeless, but many are flexible and can change based on the circumstances and needs of Muslims in different places and times. While the Sharia is comprehensive in scope\u2013as one would expect given that Islam is a complete way of life\u2013it is neither entirely static nor monolithic. Aspects of the Sharia are timeless, unchanging, and universally agreed upon. However, on any number of issues, Muslim jurists and different legal schools (or even jurists within the same legal school) may differ in their rulings. These differences of opinion may be narrow or quite wide. Additionally, interpreters of the Sharia have historically been sensitive and responsive to the changing circumstances, diverse needs, and various contexts that Muslims have found themselves in across time and place. This is a dynamism and flexibility built into the Sharia\u2013anchored in divine revelation and steered by certain broad principles and aims\u2013that has allowed it to effectively facilitate faithful and ethical Muslim life over the ages and through the present day."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Islamic spirituality?",
            "answer": "Islamic spirituality focuses on purifying one\u2019s inner being, and then on manifesting this positive inner change in daily life through ritual worship and ethical conduct. Islam teaches that God has instilled in all people a predisposition towards having faith, enjoying a meaningful relationship with God, and living a life of doing good. This predisposition is called the fitrah, and it is what causes people to embark on spiritual journeys in pursuit of truth and the meaning of life. The fitrah can only be fully satisfied when it finds God\u2019s Revelation and the teachings of His true prophets."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is Islamic spirituality unique?",
            "answer": "Islamic spirituality is holistic. It fulfills the needs of both the body and the soul, and encourages believers to manifest the highest ideals and virtues in their lives. While many approaches to spirituality separate the body from the soul, the Qur\u2019an teaches us that they are naturally interwoven. For instance, the daily Muslim prayer is a deeply spiritual practice, but it consists of both spiritual contemplation and movements of the body. This serves to move both our physical and spiritual selves towards a deeper connection with God. Another example is that physical appetites are not shamed in Islam. Instead, the natural human desires for food, drink, and intimacy should be enjoyed and celebrated (within the boundaries set by God). Living with both the body and soul in mind helps people achieve physical and emotional balance, and encourages the spiritual state of gratitude\u2014two aims that God rewards in this life and the next. Islamic spirituality also pursues societal wellbeing. Private worship is crucial for developing sincerity with God, but believers must also work to bring divine consciousness into the world. This means that every Muslim should strive to emulate divine qualities. For instance, those who are compassionate with others are closer to Allah, who is the Most Compassionate. Those who are selfless with their money and time are more in sync with God, who is the Most Generous; and those striving to end conflict understand that Allah is the Source of Peace."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Islam understand the soul?",
            "answer": "The Islamic conception of the soul is that it is not a physical thing that can be studied. Rather, the focus should be on understanding how it can help us achieve spiritual growth. The human soul is a non-physical essence that cannot be observed through any scientific instruments. Muslims focus on understanding the nature and function of the soul, rather than on questions about the soul\u2019s location or physical existence. The relationship of the soul to the body is a mystery beyond human comprehension. 'They ask you concerning the soul. Say that the soul is from the affair of my Lord and you have not been given knowledge except a portion.' [Qur\u2019an, 17:85] How can we confirm the soul\u2019s existence if it cannot be seen or fully understood? In an Islamic worldview, the function and effect of the soul are clear. It is seen in the universal drive towards spiritual experiences and beliefs. Divine ideals of beauty, love, compassion, and justice are all aims of the human soul in Islam and expressed spiritually through the mediums of art, poetry, ritual, and religious tradition. So how can we best fulfill this need to nourish the soul? God says, 'So turn your face toward the true natural way of life-God\u2019s chosen fitrah (constitution) upon which He has formed humanity. There is no altering the primary state of God\u2019s creation. That is the correct way of life, though men fail to realize it. It is the path of turning towards God, remaining dutiful to Him, establishing prayer, and being not of those who ascribe partners to Him.' [Qur\u2019an, 30:30]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is divine revelation in Islam?",
            "answer": "Divine revelation was sent to many prophets throughout history and across the world, with one united message: God alone is worthy of worship, and believers must seek to do as much good as possible. Divine revelation is consistent with Islam\u2019s conception of people as innately wired for worship, and of God as the supreme source of love, mercy, and kindness. God sent revelations throughout history to guide human beings to Him. While the fitrah\u2014the natural human tendency towards good\u2014leads people to many universal values, humans cannot know the full message of God or achieve spiritual fulfillment without revelation. Revelation was given to the prophets and messengers, who were human beings elected by God due to their moral excellence. From Adam to Moses to Jesus (peace be upon them all), each messenger was sent to spread divine knowledge and act as a role model for how to live a pious, ethical life. Through the messages that were inspired into their hearts by God, the prophets and messengers were elevated to stations of self-enlightenment and holistic virtue. This is the essence of divine revelation in Islam. The Qur\u2019an is the last and final divine revelation from God to Earth. It addresses a global audience and guides them to God. In contrast to earlier revelations, such as the Psalms of David, which were intended for a specific time and place, the Qur\u2019an is meant to be a clear message from God for humanity\u2014a culmination of all the previously revealed scriptures throughout history."
        },
        {
            "question": "How do we know the Qur\u2019an was divinely revealed?",
            "answer": "There are many proofs for the divine origin of the Qur\u2019an, including the cohesiveness of its message, the eloquence of its language, the future events it foretold, and the circumstances in which it was revealed. The Qur\u2019an is a literary masterpiece of history, guidance, and inspiration revealed through the Prophet Muhammad, who was an illiterate man. Arabs of the 7th century were masters of language and poetry, and yet, when they heard the Qur\u2019an being recited, they recognized that it was something new and special. Its language and rhythm outperformed the highest levels of their poetry and speech. When examining the Qur\u2019an, we can recognize its divine origin simply by looking at the message and the ethical worldview it presents. The focus of the entire revelation is to bring humanity towards God without any human intermediary. There was no material gain in the revelation of Islam for Prophet Muhammad, who brought this message to the world despite facing hostility, starvation, oppression, and resistance from those around him. Muhammad\u2019s selfless commitment to the mission points towards the Qur\u2019an being a genuine Divine revelation."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does Islam offer to people?",
            "answer": "Islam offers certain guidance through divine revelation (the Qur\u2019an) and prophetic tradition (the Sunnah) to provide structure, dignity, and morality to all people. It provides a consistent and logical philosophical foundation rooted in pure monotheism. It provides people with the courage and resilience to confront life\u2019s stresses, anxieties, and griefs."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is tawheed?",
            "answer": "Tawheed is the comprehensive understanding of monotheism in Islam. It describes the absolute oneness and unity of God. This version of monotheism affirms that God alone deserves to be worshiped and that He has no equal and no partners. It emphasizes that God is the singular Creator and Fashioner of all things in the universe. God can be known through His divinely revealed names and attributes in the Qur\u2019an."
        },
        {
            "question": "How do we know God exists?",
            "answer": "The Islamic understanding and case for God\u2019s existence is straightforward. Together, the faculties of heart and mind lead us to recognize God\u2019s existence. This truth of theism is accessible to everyone, regardless of background or education. Both of Islam\u2019s foundational texts show that a belief in God\u2019s existence is formed in two ways: By appealing to the heart, intuition, and experience. By appealing to the mind, logic, and reason. Conviction in God\u2019s existence comes from achieving harmony between the heart and mind. In Islamic teachings, human instincts recognize the need for a higher power as a result of a covenant made between mankind and God. In the Qur\u2019an, we learn that before the creation of the world, God gathered every soul together. In this divine gathering, mankind recognized God\u2019s existence and committed to serving as His pious earthly servants. The feelings of the heart and soul are confirmed by our intuitive understanding of the world. The purposeful creation of the universe, and the undeniable precision with which the laws of nature function, appeal to our sense of logic and reason."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why does God ask people to worship Him?",
            "answer": "Calling humanity to worship in Islam is understood as an invitation to a comprehensive life plan which includes both worship and ethical living. Through this plan, people can find purpose and fulfillment. It was from God\u2019s compassionate nature, as well as His complete knowledge about what fulfills us, that He asked us to worship Him. He does not benefit from our worship; all of the benefit of prayer is for people. Through worship, a believer receives a strong moral foundation, better understands their role in the universe, and gains access to authentic self-actualization, peace, and contentment. Worship keeps our sense of purpose constant and allows us to earn eternal rewards in every circumstance, whether it be a moment of joy or time of hardship."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Islam address destiny and free will?",
            "answer": "In addressing destiny and free will The Qur\u2019an and Sunnah follow a middle path between the two extremes of unrestricted free will and fatalism. Belief in destiny, or God\u2019s power in determining events, is one of the six articles of faith in Islam. However, Islam also notes that fate, destiny, or divine decree do not mean that people have no agency or free will. Ultimately, everyone is responsible for their own actions and choices. The early Muslims used to say in their prayers, 'O God, if You have decreed me among the damned, then wipe it away from me and affirm me among the blessed.' In other words, while Allah has willed all matters in an absolute and unchanging sense, there are portions of destiny that He allowed to be influenced by our actions. The Qur\u2019an and Sunnah follow a middle path between the extremes of complete free will and complete pre-determination. God knows about all things before they happen, and He decrees them into existence with limitless power\u2014but He also delegated a share of agency to human beings in order to fairly test their deeds, which will be evaluated on the Day of Judgment."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Islam nourish our emotional well-being?",
            "answer": "Islam provides a sense of purpose and emotional fulfillment through attachment to God. Spirituality and religiosity are also associated with better mental health and have been identified as essential aspects of preventing and treating mental illness. Islamic spirituality provides ultimate purpose and meaning to human life, and the freedom and relief that comes from surrender through worship have been shown to have profound effects on the brain. Through this framework, Islam provides the strongest anchor by which to navigate life: a deep attachment to God."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam provide guidelines on how to deal with mental illness?",
            "answer": "Yes, various types of mental illness have been discussed by Muslim scholars for centuries. Contemporary scholars recognize the need for both spiritual and clinical treatments to address mental health struggles. Many Muslim scholars have dedicated their lives to exploring the spiritual and psychological dimensions of human well-being and flourishing. In the fields of clinical psychology and psychiatry, many practitioners increasingly recognize the role of spirituality as an essential part of both the prevention and treatment of mental illness. A systematic review of multiple studies showed that increased levels of spirituality and religiosity in adolescence correlated with better mental health."
        },
        {
            "question": "How can one understand and navigate sadness and grief in Islam?",
            "answer": "Islamic texts acknowledge the validity of negative emotions and offer guidelines on how to deal with them in a healthy way. One of the first steps Islam takes in navigating such emotions is to reorient our perspective and remind us not to become overly attached to this world. It is normal to experience sadness and grief, and these emotions can be beneficial and a means of drawing nearer to God if dealt with appropriately. Muslim scholars have offered practical approaches to addressing these emotions, such as the Duha Approach."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does Islam teach about managing anxiety, depression, and self-doubt?",
            "answer": "Islamic teachings validate negative emotions and mindsets, and from these teachings, we can derive practical tips to overcome them. The Qur\u2019an describes human nature as prone to anxiety and fear. Some practical steps from the Islamic tradition to deal with negative emotions include practicing the sunnah of husn al-dhann, recalling the Prophet's struggles, reminding oneself of the blessings and opportunities in difficulties, and striving to remember that Allah is always with us."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are Muslims punished for hating their life or wanting to end it?",
            "answer": "No, even the most pious people experienced moments of despair. However, the Prophet instructed us not to pray for death. In general, we should approach life as something categorically good and keep negative things in perspective. Along the way, we should not suffer alone or in silence and seek help when we are struggling."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are there Qur\u2019anic prescriptions for coping and distress?",
            "answer": "Yes, the Qur\u2019an uses stories to provide relatability and offers coping strategies to feel better about temporary negativity and distress. The Qur\u2019an teaches us that even the greatest of people experienced periods of profound distress, grief, or sorrow, and we can learn from this that such emotions are a normal part of the human experience. Seeking solace by visualizing the promise of eternal happiness in Paradise, striving to remember God frequently, and turning to God with complaints and pains in prayer and supplication are all actions inspired by Quranic guidance that help us through negative emotions."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is tazkiyah?",
            "answer": "Tazkiyah is the process of working to purify the heart and soul. Muslims use a number of terms to describe the important process of purifying or refining the heart and soul, including tazkiyah, tazkiyyat al-nafs, ihsan, and tasawwuf. All of these terms point to Islam\u2019s emphasis on striving to attain a refined and purified inward state in harmony with the commands of Allah."
        },
        {
            "question": "How can one purify their heart and soul?",
            "answer": "The steps towards purifying or adorning oneself with virtues and vices include the practice of exercising mindfulness, repentance, performing good deeds, and striving to perfect and beautify one\u2019s character. Among the objectives of tazkiyah are to cultivate virtues such as taqwa, sincerity, truthfulness, generosity, forbearance, forgiveness, patience, and modesty, and to remove vices such as heedlessness, dishonesty, stinginess, envy, and shamelessness."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are OCD tendencies a result of Satanic whispers?",
            "answer": "OCD may be caused by both external (Satanic) and internal (self or biological) sources. Being overcome by excessive thoughts is not a sign of low faith or defectiveness. Unwanted, obsessive thoughts relating to religiosity are classified as a specific form of OCD known as scrupulosity, and those who suffer from it require a treatment plan that involves both effective cognitive behavioral therapy and Islamic interventions with a religious leader."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does the Quran describe happiness? How does one achieve it in Islam?",
            "answer": "Happiness through the lens of Islam is of two kinds: happiness in this world and happiness in the hereafter. The Qur\u2019an does not disparage the life of this world, but believers enjoy the goods of this world while working towards the higher goods of the next. Happiness depends on our attitude towards this world and how we live in it. If we are engrossed in the material world, we will forget the ultimate purpose of our creation. According to al-Ghazali, the moderate way of living is like the lives of the Prophets, since it fulfills both the needs of this world and the hereafter."
        },
        {
            "question": "Do the Quran and Sunnah offer guidance on how to deal with trauma and pain?",
            "answer": "Yes, the Duha Approach is one example of how the religious tradition offers guidance on dealing with trauma and pain. This approach is based on the chapter of the Quran known as ad-Duha and mirrors its structure. It involves establishing a sense of attachment and connection to Allah, shifting perspective and reminding ourselves of the blessings Allah has bestowed upon us, taking action to better our patterns of behavior and mindsets, and cultivating gratitude."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam promote violence?",
            "answer": "No, Islam does not promote unprovoked violence. Islam governs by a primary set of principles known as maqasid ash-shariah: the preservation of religion, life, intellect, progeny, and property. The value of human life is emphasized in Islam\u2019s sacred texts, the Qur\u2019an and Sunnah. The Qur\u2019an equates a single murder with the killing of humankind at large, and equates saving a single life with rescuing all of humanity. The Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa defined the faithful as \u201cthose most restrained from violence\u201d. Islam even forbids sports that use animals as targets, or involve striking the face of a fellow human being. However, tyranny and crimes against humanity are an unfortunate fact of the human condition, so Islam engages this reality by sometimes allowing physical force as a deterrent, and regulating it with ethical parameters, to ensure the best possible outcome for society and the world."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam permit the killing of civilians?",
            "answer": "Islam does not permit the killing of civilians. No classical Muslim scholar has ever condoned the killing of civilians, even in the midst of a justified war. Indiscriminate acts of violence against civilians, which are often attributed to Islam, have zero precedent in Islamic teachings. It is for this reason that car bombings, suicide bombings, mass shootings, and other crimes committed by self-identified Muslims are so strongly condemned by Muslim leaders and communities around the world. In Islam, the deliberate targeting of civilians in war is categorically unjustified, going against both the higher aims of Islamic law to protect all life, as well as the universal Islamic maxim which criminalizes any and all avoidable harm."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does jihad mean?",
            "answer": "Jihad is a broad Arabic term that, at its core, means to expend one\u2019s efforts in a good cause despite the adversity involved. Islam\u2019s scriptures use the term jihad in a variety of contexts. The Qur\u2019an refers to the jihad of preaching an unpopular truth (25:52), the jihad of pursuing guidance despite obstacles (29:69), and the jihad of resisting the persecution of oneself (2:190) and others (4:75). The Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa also used the term jihad in the context of speaking truth to power, seeking knowledge, selflessly serving one\u2019s parents, and battling the evil within one\u2019s soul."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is jihad misinterpreted as terrorism?",
            "answer": "Armed jihad is a last resort governed by strict rules. The groups we see today claiming to be performing jihad violate those rules. Armed conflict could fall under \u201cjihad\u201d when certain conditions deem it necessary, such as the faith or safety of Muslims being physically threatened, human rights being overrun, or when people\u2019s freedom to practice, preach, and embrace Islam is suppressed. Islam has strict legal conditions for the use of force as a last resort, which includes the safety of civilians and non-military property, and the forbidding of treachery, mutilation, and plunder. These rules of military jihad, in many ways, preceded what would later become the modern just-war theory."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does the Qur\u2019an say to kill the non-believers?",
            "answer": "This verse is frequently quoted out of context and with a lack of understanding. One of the most misquoted sentences in the Qur\u2019an is: \u201cKill them wherever you find them\u201d (2:191). Reading this passage in its full context, and knowing how extensively peace, justice, and compassion permeate the Qur\u2019anic message, is sufficient to neutralize the misuse of this verse above. This verse is speaking about active combatants (2:190), and specifically attackers whom the believers feared they would be forced to confront in a place which the Qur\u2019an deemed a sacred precinct; a place so sacred that even cutting a tree or frightening a bird was prohibited therein. Therefore, this verse simply establishes a concession to fend off assailants, regardless of where they may be encountered."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam allow preemptive war?",
            "answer": "Islam allows preemptive war only after a fair declaration of war, where a credible threat exists, never in violation of a peace treaty or truce, and never with those inclined to peace. The Western concept of preemptive war, or a war launched to neutralize an actual threat or impending attack, is similar to the concept of \u201coffensive jihad\u201d (jihad al-talab) in Islam. Offensive jihad is when a Muslim country\u2019s army engages another military force beyond its borders. This must occur after a fair declaration of war (i.e., where a credible threat is made), never in violation of a peace treaty or truce, and never with those inclined to peace."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are there specific codes of war in Islam?",
            "answer": "Yes, Islam has many regulations to minimize the destruction of any war. The loss of life is minimized by strict rules against targeting civilians and noncombatants. The loss of property is minimized by rules against pillaging lands and cutting down trees. Also, prisoners of war must be treated humanely, and believers are encouraged to release them unconditionally, or for a reasonable ransom, or by providing them realistic ways to free themselves through fair labor. The ultimate and overarching goal of Islamic law is to minimize harm and maximize benefit for society as a whole. At times, this may require taking up arms to secure peace. In those cases, sacred laws restrain Muslim armies from taking advantage of an enemy and hold them to the most morally upright codes of conduct in war. The Qur\u2019an also states that wars should be ended as quickly as possible: \u201cAnd if they incline to peace, then incline to it [also] and rely upon Allah. Indeed, it is He who is the Hearing, the Knowing.\u201d (8:61)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Did Islam spread through violence and forced conversions?",
            "answer": "The spread of Islam occurred through religious propagation, trade, intermarriage, migration, the universality of Islam, and its emphasis on justice and unity. Historians have widely discredited the narrative that Islam is widespread in the world today because of forced conversions. While exceptional cases of forced conversions did exist, these were clear violations of Islamic guidelines and never the norm. Forced conversions are clearly forbidden in Islam. God says in the Qur\u2019an, \u201cThere is no compulsion in religion,\u201d (2:256). Forcing someone to practice Islam defeats the purpose of the religion\u2014for individuals to build a sincere and genuine relationship with their Creator."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does Islam treat religious minorities?",
            "answer": "Religious tolerance was historically a hallmark of Muslim societies. Religious minorities were known in Islamic history as dhimmis, or the \u201cprotected class\u201d, which reflected the fact that under Islamic law, they enjoyed the dhimmah (protection) of God, in which they could live in security and practice their religion without harassment. The presence of other religious communities within Muslim majority countries today is perhaps one of the clearest proofs against the claim that Islam requires non-Muslims to convert or face the sword. Many non-Muslim minorities had thriving communities within the capitols of major cities under Islamic control for centuries (there were Christian quarters in Damascus, Jerusalem, and Coptic Cairo, for example) where they operated under their own religious court systems."
        },
        {
            "question": "Is blasphemy punishable by death?",
            "answer": "The Qur\u2019an tells Muslims who encounter blasphemy or offenses to God and His religion to simply turn away until the conversation changes (6:68, 4:140). When the pagans of Quraysh would call the Prophet \u2018mudhammam\u2019 (the disgraced) instead of his name Muhammad (the oft-praised), he would gracefully say to his followers, \u201cAren\u2019t you amazed that God has even averted the insults of the Quraysh? They revile a man named Mudhammam, while I am Muhammad!\u201d (Sahih Bukhari). Historically, an attack on the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa meant a rebellion against the constitution of the Muslim state. While Muslim scholars had different opinions about the penalty for insulting the Prophet \ufdfa, major early scholars such as Abu Hanifah and al-Bukhari believed there should be no punishment at all, because a non-Muslim\u2019s disbelief in Islam is already assumed. Scholars note that those executed in the Prophet\u2019s \ufdfa lifetime were warmongers and menaces to society, not simply insulters or peaceful opponents. Also, legal punishments in Islam are only enforceable by a governing authority, and so the duty of the average Muslim is to adopt the Prophet\u2019s gentle character, clarify misinformation about him, and advocate for a harmonious society that rejects the desecration of any religious symbols or personalities."
        },
        {
            "question": "Is apostasy punishable by death in Islam?",
            "answer": "Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa did not punish a single apostate in his entire life solely for leaving the faith. Following this precedent, many contemporary Muslim jurists choose not to punish apostates for leaving Islam. Punishing apostasy has roots in Judaism, Christianity, and Islam. It may be difficult to grasp why this was ever considered necessary, due to how little religion affects wider society in our secular age. In pre-modern times, religious identity played a major role in defining individuals and nations. As a result, leaving one\u2019s faith would be seen as a rebellion against public order and a subversion of the common good. For example, European Christians who embraced Islam were often referred to as \u201cRenegades\u201d and would risk their lives to remain in Europe, as a religious conversion was widely seen as treason and a declaration of hostility. In the past, Muslim jurists have held that clear apostasy was a capital crime for which a person may be killed. This does not mean that mobs of Muslim carried out executions, or that officials hunted down apostates inquisition-style. This could only be acted on by the government, and they were only to act on public claims of apostasy, and confirmed offenders were urged to recant as a way to completely avoid any consequences. Many contemporary Muslim jurists choose not to punish apostates for leaving Islam, in accordance with international agreements on religious freedoms, as well as the precedent set by Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa, who did not punish a single apostate in his entire life solely for leaving the faith."
        },
        {
            "question": "Does Islam Allow Honor Killings?",
            "answer": "Islamic law has a zero tolerance policy on honor killings, drawing on clear rulings set by the Prophet Muhammad \ufdfa. According to Islamic law, any husband who kills his wife or illicit partner has committed murder, even if he was indirectly involved in her death. Islam is not the culprit, but part of the solution, for honor crimes. Islam effectively reforms the cultural and legal systems that perpetuate honor killings, or fail at combating them, through its serious warnings against violating the safety of innocent people in general, and condemning the abuse of women in particular. Violence against women is a universal problem that extends far beyond a specific religion or region. To depict it as inherent to Muslim societies as a result of Islamic teachings is not only dishonest, but works to downplay the true extent of this global problem. Such narratives only get in the way of efforts to protect the safety and dignity of all women, and disparage the Islamic teachings that have lessened the prevalence of those who prey on women in this tragic way."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Hajj?",
            "answer": "Hajj is a sacred pilgrimage, performed annually by Muslims, to Masjid al-Haram (the Sacred Mosque erected by Prophet Abraham) in Mecca. It is the 5th pillar of Islam and is expected to be completed once in a Muslim\u2019s lifetime."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is Hajj important?",
            "answer": "The importance of Hajj is not limited to it being an opportunity to seek forgiveness for past sins but it allows believers to connect to Prophet Abraham (pbuh) and Prophet Muhammad (pbuh) through the rituals of Hajj. The Hajj pilgrimage also brings together the global Muslim community from all corners of the world, synchronized in a profound ritual before the One God as a single family despite their differences in race, ethnicity, and ages."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where does Hajj take place?",
            "answer": "Hajj takes place in and around the holy city of Mecca, located in present day Saudi Arabia. Some of the Hajj rites take place at the Ka\u2019bah (the epicenter of Ancient Mosque built by Prophet Abraham), others at the nearby hills of Safa and Marwa (where Hagar sought drinking water for her child), and others outside the mosque at Mina, Muzdalifa, and Mount Arafah."
        },
        {
            "question": "When is Hajj?",
            "answer": "Hajj occurs during the first 13 days of the month of Dhul-Hijjah, the 12th or last month of the Islamic (lunar) Calendar with the rituals starting primarily on the 8th day of Dhul-Hijjah. In 2024, Hajj will begin on June 14th and the day of Arafat will take place on June 15th. These dates are tentative until the new moon is sighted at the beginning of the month."
        },
        {
            "question": "How long does Hajj last?",
            "answer": "Hajj typically lasts 5-6 days, starting on the 8th or 9th day of Dhul-Hijjah, the last month of the Islamic (lunar) Calendar, and ending on the 12th or 13th day of Dhul-Hijjah."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is required to perform Hajj?",
            "answer": "Hajj is required by all physically and financially able Muslims. It is required to be performed once in a Muslim\u2019s lifetime."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is Hajj performed?",
            "answer": "Hajj is comprised of 6 main rituals \u2013 Ihram, Arafat, Jamarat, Udhiya, Sa\u2019i, and Tawaf. The steps include: 1) Go into a state of Ihram and make intention to perform Hajj. 2) Proceed to Mina, where the day is spent in prayer. 3) From Mina, head to Arafat, where the day is spent in prayer. 4) After sunset, proceed to Muzdalifa. 5) Depart Muzdalifa to Mina for Jamarat. 6) After Jamarat, pilgrims will perform Udhiya. 7) Men will trim or shave their heads and women will trim a finger length of their hair. 8) Pilgrims will then proceed to Ka\u2019bah to perform Tawaf. 9) When complete, pilgrims will return to Mina to repeat Jamarat ritual and then return back to Mecca and perform Farewell Tawaf."
        },
        {
            "question": "Are Umrah and Hajj the same?",
            "answer": "Umrah and Hajj are not the same. The importance and reward of Hajj is bigger than that of Umrah, but it can only be performed during a specific time of the year, and it involves significantly more steps. Umrah can be performed anytime during the year, and only requires four of the rituals performed during Hajj\u2014Ihram, Tawaf, Sa\u2019i and Taqsir."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Umrah?",
            "answer": "Umrah in Arabic means \u201cto visit a populated place.\u201d It is a shorter version of Hajj, and is also known as the \u201clesser pilgrimage.\u201d Umrah can be performed anytime during the year. Many people perform Umrah multiple times, each with the intention of connecting with God and seeking forgiveness for past sins."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is Umrah performed?",
            "answer": "Umrah is performed at Masjid al-Haram in the holy city of Makkah (Mecca)."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is Umrah performed?",
            "answer": "Umrah consists of four main rituals: Ihram, Tawaf, Sa\u2019i and Taqsir. The steps include: 1) Prepare for Ihram by bathing and donning Ihram garments. 2) Enter the state of Ihram by making an intention to perform Umrah and reciting Talbiyah. 3) Enter Masjid Al-Haram and perform Tawaf. 4) Move towards Mount Safa to begin Sa\u2019i, then walk between Mount Safa and Mount Marwa seven times. 5) Once Sa\u2019i is complete, pilgrims complete their Umrah by shaving their heads (only men) or shortening their hair (men and women)."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Ka\u2019bah (Kaaba)?",
            "answer": "The Ka\u2019bah (Kaaba) is the original house of worship on Earth, an ancient structure built by God\u2019s command to serve as a symbol of monotheism throughout the ages. It is the direction that every believer faces in their daily worship of God."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who built the Ka\u2019bah (Kaaba)?",
            "answer": "The Qur\u2019an clearly establishes that Prophet Abraham (pbuh) erected the pillars of the Ka'bah, along with his son, Ishmael (pbuh). Scholars debate, however, over whether this verse meant he was the first to establish the Ka\u2019bah, or if 'erected its pillars' meant restoring it following a command from God."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the Ka\u2019bah (Kaaba)?",
            "answer": "The Ka\u2019bah is located in the center of the Holy Mosque, Masjid Al-Haram, in the city of Makkah (Mecca), Saudi Arabia."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is the Ka\u2019bah (Kaaba) important?",
            "answer": "The Ka\u2019bah is important because it represents the 'House of God' on Earth. It is also the direction that Muslims around the world face when performing the five daily prayers, which represents the unity of Muslims in the worship of the One True God."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Prophet Ibrahim?",
            "answer": "Prophet Ibrahim (pbuh), or Abraham, was a prophet and messenger of God. He is an important figure in Judaism, Christianity and Islam. In Islam, he is known for his refusal to worship idols, instead choosing to worship the One God. It was Prophet Ibrahim (pbuh) who raised the pillars of the Ka\u2019bah together with the help of his son, Prophet Ishmael (pbuh)."
        }
    ]
}